rayjobs.com 2015-05-29

# PRIVACY POLICY

                                          PRIVACY POLICY
This Privacy Policy applies to any visitor or user (hereinafter referred to as “You”) of the website
located at www.raytheon.com and any websites (singularly and collectively, “the Site”) that
Raytheon Company or its subsidiaries (singularly and collectively, “Raytheon”) own and
control. Raytheon is sensitive to the issue of confidentiality in online dealings and is committed
to protecting individual privacy. This Privacy Policy is intended to inform users about the
general approach Raytheon uses in collecting, using and disseminating user information via the
Site. Additionally, as the Site includes www.mathmovesu.com, a website designed to engage
middle school students in math by illustrating the connection between math, their interests, and
"cool" careers, the Site may be of interest to children under the age of 13 years old. We are
committed to complying fully with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”).
Our information collection policy is described below. We urge children who are under the age
of 13 to check with their parent or guardian before entering any personally identifiable
information on or through the Site.
1. What Personally Identifiable Information May Be Collected?
1.1 At Raytheon, it is our policy to create website content that requires minimal collection of
personally identifiable information from our visitors. However, to respond to your requests or to
enable you to register or to use certain features of this Site, we may request personally
identifiable information from you including, but not limited to, your name, home address, email
address and/or telephone number. We do not collect any more personally identifiable
information than is reasonably necessary to enable your participation in the activities we offer.
For example, we may need your name and email address to add you to an email update list, or
we may require a home address and telephone number to enter you into a contest or sweepstakes,
such as those found on www.mathmovesu.com. If we know that a user is under the age of 13,
we will obtain a parent’s permission before we collect or share your personally identifiable
information with any third party except as otherwise set forth in this Privacy Policy. Please note
that parents may consent to the collection and use of personally identifiable information without
consenting to the disclosure of such information to third parties.
1.2 When we do collect personally identifiable information, we will only keep it until that
particular activity (or set of activities) is complete. Generally, your personally identifiable
information will not be given out to third parties not affiliated with Raytheon, however, from
time to time we may transfer, disclose or share your personally identifiable information with
third parties who may be engaged by us specifically to handle and deliver certain online
activities, including, but not limited to, conducting contests and sweepstakes, such as those found
on www.mathmovesu.com. Such parties will have access to your personally identifiable
information needed to perform these functions, but may not use it for other purposes.
1.3 Our Site may provide links to other websites that may have their own information collection
practices. To the extent that you provide personally identifiable information to websites that link
to or from our Site, different rules may apply to the use and disclosure of your personally
identifiable information. To the extent that the Site includes third-party advertisements, the
privacy policy of the advertiser providing the advertisement will govern the use of your
personally identifiable information collected during your access to the advertisement. Raytheon

does not control linking practices of advertisers or sponsors and does not monitor or claim
responsibility for any content or privacy practices of such websites. Once you have clicked on
an advertisement and have left our Site, you must read the privacy policy of the advertiser or
sponsor to see how your personally identifiable information will be handled.
1.4 On occasion, Raytheon may use an advertising server developed by a third party to display
ads on our Site. Some of these ads may contain cookies that are set by third parties (advertisers,
sponsors). We do not have access to these cookies or any information that they contain. This
Privacy Policy does not cover any use of information that a third-party ad server may have
collected from you.
1.5 Raytheon may use the Site as an entry into other networked web pages and websites operated
by Raytheon and its subsidiaries and affiliates (together, the "Transaction Sites"), exclusive of
www.mathmovesu.com, for which this section does not apply. Please note that individual
Transaction Sites may adopt privacy terms particular to the purpose of such Transaction Site or
the transaction(s) taking place on such Transaction Site. As Transaction Sites are generally
affiliated with commercial transactions that you or your business may have with Raytheon,
particularly those which are password-protected or are subject to subscriptions, you understand
that the privacy terms for such sites may differ through terms in separate agreements which may
supplement or supersede these terms.
2. Other Types of Information That May Be Collected
2.1 IP Addresses
An Internet protocol address, or IP address, is automatically assigned to your computer when you
access the Internet, and is used by web servers to identify your computer. When you access our
Site, we may log your IP address, however, your identity will remain anonymous to us. We log
the IP addresses for system administration and for auditing the use of our Site. We may also use
IP addresses to collect statistical information for marketing and other purposes.
2.2 Cookies or Tracers
From time to time, we may place information on your computer to allow us to identify you. This
information is known as a “cookie”. We will only use cookies to view information on User’s
computer’s hard drive that was placed there by a cookie from our Site, such as your preferences
or which pages you have visited on the Site. However, a cookie will not allow our Site to learn
any personally identifiable information that you have not otherwise disclosed (except as
described below). By understanding how and when our visitors use the Site, we can continually
improve our Site, as well as our products and services. If you wish to disable cookies, your
browser can be reset to refuse all cookies or indicate when a cookie is being sent.
In some instances, we use tracking scripts or "tracers" that recognize a unique identifier from a
cookie placed on your hard drive by another website. These are used by Raytheon solely to
gauge the success of our own advertising. For instance, we may use a tracer to determine
whether you visit our employment pages after visiting a resume or career site where Raytheon
placed a banner ad. We do not use tracers to gather information on your use of the Internet
unrelated to Raytheon. Please note that Raytheon does not use tracers to determine your
personally identifiable information, and you remain anonymous.

2.3 Web Beacons
Web beacons are small files that we may place on our Site, which count the number of unique
users that have visited a specific page on the Site and the number of times a given page has been
displayed. This information is collected only in the aggregate and is generally not linked to any
personally identifiable information (except as described below).
2.4 What happens if I register?
Registration may be allowed or required on the Site. Please refer to the agreements and policies
applicable to the Site for which you provide registration information in order to assure that you
understand the applicable privacy practices. Raytheon may collect registration data in order to
monitor compliance with this Privacy Policy and to set up access permissions to certain other
pages on the Site.
3. Use of Information
3.1 Use and Sharing of Information
Raytheon and its affiliates may use and disclose your personally identifiable information only as
set forth herein. Anonymous data collected using cookies and web beacons may be analyzed in
the aggregate to determine collective user characteristics, to understand user traffic patterns,
sales information and user behavior on the Site. Such information also may be shared in the
aggregate with third parties for advertising purposes, to enhance our Site, to enhance our
products and services, and to analyze how and where best to use our resources.
3.2 Monitoring and Compliance
Although Raytheon is under no obligation to monitor the Site, we may monitor, store, review and
disclose to third parties any information, including your personally identifiable information,
obtained on or through the Site as may be needed or requested to satisfy any applicable
governmental law, regulation, investigation or proceeding. Additionally, we may use IP
addresses to identify a particular user if we believe it is needed to enforce compliance with these
terms or to protect our company, employees, Site, or customers.
4. Security of Personally Identifiable Information
4.1 While Raytheon tries to prevent third party, non-affiliate access to personally identifiable
information, you should keep in mind that data transmission over the Internet is not 100% secure
and any information disclosed online can potentially be collected and used other than by the
intended recipient. In view of the foregoing, Raytheon cannot warrant that your personally
identifiable information will not be disclosed to or accessed by parties other than those
authorized under this Privacy Policy.
5. Updates to Your Information
5.1 At your request, Raytheon will make reasonable efforts to update, change or delete any
personally identifiable information you have provided via the Site. In order to enforce the terms
of this Privacy Policy, resolve disputes, or provide information to satisfy applicable
governmental laws, regulations, investigations or proceedings, we may need to retain your

personally identifiable information in our files. Additionally, your personally identifiable
information may be retained in residual back-up files that are a function of our network’s back-
up systems.
6. COPPA Specifically
6.1 Raytheon encourages parents and guardians to spend time online with their children. We
urge parents to instruct their children never to give out their real names, addresses, or phone
numbers without the permission of a parent or guardian, when using the Internet. We recognize
a special obligation to protect personal information obtained from children, as may be collected
on the Site, specifically at www.mathmovesu.com.
In compliance with COPPA, we have adopted the following policies to keep children safe (there
are a few exceptions to these policies as noted below under the heading "Exceptions to Verifiable
Parental Consent"):
    A. We will not knowingly collect, use, or distribute personally identifiable information from
    children under the age of 13 without prior verifiable consent from a parent or guardian.
    B. Personally identifiable information we collect from children under the age of 13 will be
    used solely by Raytheon or its agents for internal purposes only and will not be sold or
    otherwise distributed to third parties.
    C. We will not knowingly allow children under the age of 13 to access, any social media site
    that may exist on the Site, email accounts, or other services within Raytheon that would
    allow them to publicly post or otherwise distribute personally identifiable information
    without prior verifiable consent from a parent or guardian.
    D. We will not knowingly ask a child under the age of 13 to divulge more information than
    is needed to participate in any activity, game, or service.
    E. We will not knowingly keep any personally identifiable information that is inadvertently
    included in a child's email submission, help inquiry, or other one-time request, if we know
    that the child is under the age of 13. Information will be automatically purged or purged
    immediately after the issue has been resolved.
    F. We will not knowingly post any personally identifiable information that is inadvertently
    included in a child's submission to a general audience contribution area if we know that the
    child is under the age of 13. These submissions will be deleted and handled anonymously
    thereafter.
    G. We will not knowingly provide any direct link to websites that are unsuitable for children
    or teens.
    H. We will advise children under the age of 13 that they must obtain permission from their
    parent or guardian before sharing any personal information.

    I. Upon request, we will provide a parent or guardian with a description of the information
    that may have been provided about their child during a registration process for a program,
    service or contest on the Site. We only ask for a child's or teen's personally identifiable
    information if it is necessary to participate in the foregoing.
7. Notification and Verifiable Parental Consent
7.1 Before any personally identifiable information is collected, we will do our best to notify the
parent or guardian that their child is participating. Notification will include the exact nature and
intended use of the information we are collecting, as well as the opportunity for the parent or
guardian to prevent the use of the information and the child's participation in the activity. For
every child (anyone under 13 years of age) we require the parent or guardian to provide
verifiable parental consent such as an email, mail-in letter, fax, or toll-free phone call to
Raytheon.
8. Exceptions to Verifiable Parental Consent
8.1 There are few instances where we will not get verifiable parental consent, such as:
    A. Requesting the contact information of a parent or guardian for the sole purpose of
    obtaining verifiable parental consent or providing notification to the parent or guardian;
    B. Collecting a child's contact information solely to directly respond to the child's request on
    a one-time basis. We will not use that information to re-contact the child for any other
    purpose (we will purge from our system the child's personal information after responding);
    and
    C. Collecting a child's contact information and the contact information of his/her parent or
    guardian solely to directly respond more than once to a specific request from the child (for
    example, to satisfy the request for a newsletter subscription). In this instance, the parent or
    guardian will be notified that the child made such a request and be informed of the
    information provided by the child. The parent or guardian will have an opportunity at any
    time to revoke the child's request (i.e., unsubscribe). We will not use the child's personal
    information to re-contact the child for any other purpose.
9. External Links
9.1 Occasionally, you will find links from our Site to independently owned, controlled, and/or
managed websites whose content we believe will be of possible interest and value to our visitors.
9.2 In many cases, these links represent cooperative projects or mutual links established with the
organizations connected with these sites. We don't control the content of the sites accessed by
you via these links. These other sites may send you their own cookies, collect data, or solicit
personal information. While we identify sponsor and advertiser areas of our Site, we do not
control these cookies or the content of these third parties.
9.3 Once you leave our servers (you can generally tell where you are by checking the URL in the
location bar on your browser), the use of any information you provide is governed by the privacy

policy of the operator of the site you are visiting. That policy may differ from ours. If you can't
find the privacy policy of any of these sites via a link from that site's home page, you should
contact that website operator directly for more information.
9.4 We specifically recommend that children check with their parents or teachers before
connecting to any new websites.
10. Contact Information
10.1 If you have any questions or concerns regarding Raytheon’s privacy policy, please contact
us at:
Vice President, Intellectual Property and Licensing
RAYTHEON COMPANY
Waltham Woods
870 Winter Street
Waltham, MA 02451-1449
